Guide to the Michael Kammen papers and Department of History senior honors theses, 1962-2014.
Kammen, Michael, papers and Department of History senior honors theses
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of History. Senior Honors Theses, 1962-2007
14-17-3649
Kammen, Michael G.
1.8 cubic ft.; 5 videotapes.
23 senior honors theses, articles, videos.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Theses written under Professor Kammen's direction; talks, articles, and papers written by Michael Kammen, and drafts, galley proofs, and source material for a book he edited.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Theses written under Professor Kammen's direction.
Videotapes of talks given by Michael Kammen, including Public Affairs Television Moyers, "In Search of the Constitution: In the Beginning," 1987; White House Millennium, 1998; Fall Festival of the Arts and National Conference Keynote Address, Michigan State University, 1999; Ball State University, 2000.
Papers and articles by Michael Kammen, and drafts, galley proofs, and source material for a book he edited.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kammen, Michael G.; Becker, Carl L. (Carl Lotus), 1873-1945.
Subjects:
United States--History--Study and teaching.
Forms:
Theses.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Senior honors theses: Box 1-2
Articles/papers/book by Michael Kammen: Box 3-4
Videos/CD's: Box 3
CONTAINER LIST
- Senior honors theses (Box 1-2)
  - Changing American Perceptions of Puritanism, 1915-1944; Grant, Elizabeth M., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family and Community in Leominster, Massachusetts, 1740-1800; DiNardo, Bennie, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History by the House: a case study in the Political, Social and Urban Context of Patriotic Preservationism; Relkin, Ellen, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Vision of an Historical Novelist: A Biographical Study of Esther Forbes, 1891-1967; McCabe, Beth, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Influence of Slavery Upon the California Constitution of 1849; Berger, Matthew D., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Whole Gospel of National Newspaper Advertising": American Newspapers and Newspaper Advertising, 1885-1925; Konstance, Suzanne, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Educational Policy in American History Museums, 1940-1975; Schafer, Julie, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Creating a Spirit of Place: Ward Melville, The Three Villages and visions of community in 20th century America; Hull, Jennifer, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - War in Four Colors: The Portrayal of War in American Comic Books, 1940-1955; Soffer, Philip, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Melting Pot to Mosaic: The Movement for Recognition of White Ethnic American, 1969-1975; Kelman, Matthew S., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Happier Side of Negro Life": Moderation, Imitation, and African-American Identity in Ebony's "Photo-Editorials," 1945-1978; Smith, Arthur C., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Fine Print: Diversity Within the Groups Involved in "The Perfect Moment" Controversy and the Role of the American Press; Swarz, Lynn M., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Confronting the Doorkeeper: Assessing Myth in American Law, 1930-1960; Greenblatt, Joshua, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "On the Other Side of the Wall": The Role of the Media During the 1971 Attica Prison Uprising; Kraft-Stolar, Tamar, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographing the Landscape of the Soul: Sites of Identity in Nineteenth-Century American Portrait Photographs and Regional Narratives; Anderson, Alicia Kate, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Double and Its Wilderness in two parts; Anderson, Erica Kendall, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "I Am With You, You Men and Women of Generations Hence": Walt Whitman's Influence on Arts and Writers of the American Scene; Guarneri, Julia A., 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A Camera Lucida: Antebellum British Travelers' Narratives and the Invention of America; Peters, Justin, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Elusive Life of Robert Hare or A Contextualized Profile of an Individual Lamentably Lost from the Annals of History; Silberman, Michael J., 2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Biennale as Battlefield: The Museum of Modern Art and the CIA at the Venice Biennale, 1948-1956; Somerstein, Rachel, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - When Push Comes to Shove: A Comparative Analysis of the Changing role of Dance Within the French and American State Funding Institutions; Faissié, Nathalie, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Burt Green Wilder: Scientific Pioneer in American Racial Thought, 1841-1925; Harris, Brianna Noelani, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Conflicted Critics: Culture, Politics and the New York intellectuals; Noonan, Madeline, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Articles/papers/book by Michael Kammen (Box 3-4)
  - "Richard Watson Gilder and the New York Tenement House Commission of 1894", 1962 (Box 3)
    -article in Bulletin of the New York Public Library
  - "The Origins of Representative Government in British North America", 1968 (Box 3)
  - "The American Colonies and the 'Seasons of Business' in Eighteenth-Century Britain", 1970 (Box 3)
    -article in Anciens Pays et Assemblees D'Etats
  - "A Machine That Would Go of Itself", 1988 (Box 3)
    -in Korean
  - Two articles in Cyrillic script, 1981, 1998 (Box 3)
  - "What is the Good of History?" drafts, galley proofs, and source material, circa 1973 (Box 4)
    Drafts, galley proofs, and photocopies of primary source material from various libraries for "'What is the Good of History?": Selected Letters of Carl L. Becker, 1900-1945, edited by Kammen.
- Videos/CD's (Box 3)
  - "In Search of the Constitution: In the Beginning", 1987; V-5970 (Box 3)
  - "White House Millennium", 1998; V-5971 (Box 3)
  - Tocqueville lecture, Library of Congress, 1998; V-5972 (Box 3)
  - Fall Festival of the Arts and National Conference, keynote address, 1999; V-5973 (Box 3)
  - "1950 at Fifty: A Watershed Year in American Culture and Its Legacy", Ball State University, 2000; V-5974 (Box 3)
  - "Booknotes: Michael Kammen", 1999; V-5990 (Box 3)
  - "Visual Shock" by Michael Kammen - Off The Page, 2007; CD-1680 (Box 3)